[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "A queue follows the Last In, First Out (LIFO) principle.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "In an array-based queue, the front pointer points to the first element in the queue.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "A linked list implementation of a queue requires a fixed size.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The enqueue operation adds an element to the rear of the queue.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "A queue is an example of an Abstract Data Type (ADT).",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "In a queue, elements are removed from the rear.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "A circular queue helps to efficiently utilize memory by reusing empty spaces.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "In a linked list-based queue, each node contains data and a pointer to the next node.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The ‘isFull()’ operation is used in both array and linked list implementations of a queue.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Queues are commonly used in process scheduling and task management.",
      "answer": true
    }
  ]
  